<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' standalone='yes'?>


<!-- DO NOT EDIT THIS FILE ... YOU WILL LOSE YOUR WORK -->


<c74object name='ambitap.xtc~' category='audio,  spatial,  binaural,  transaural,  loudspeakers'>

	<digest>Crosstalk cancellation (transaural): play stereo or binaural program over two loudspeakers at a known span and distance so each ear hears only its own channel</digest>
	<description>Crosstalk cancellation (transaural): play stereo or binaural program over two loudspeakers at a known span and distance so each ear hears only its own channel. Regularized KEMAR plant inverse (computed-plant presets, AmbiTap dsp::xtc); parameter changes crossfade click-free. </description>


	<!--METADATA-->

	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name='author'>Timothy Place </metadata>
		<metadata name='tag'>audio</metadata>
		<metadata name='tag'>spatial</metadata>
		<metadata name='tag'>binaural</metadata>
		<metadata name='tag'>transaural</metadata>
		<metadata name='tag'>loudspeakers</metadata>
	</metadatalist>


	<!--ARGUMENTS-->

	<objarglist>

	</objarglist>


	<!--MESSAGES-->

	<methodlist>

	</methodlist>


	<!--ATTRIBUTES-->

	<attributelist>

		<attribute name='regularization' get='1' set='1' type='float64' size='1' >
			<digest>In-band regularization amount, 0..1 (default 0.5 — the verified setting)</digest>
			<description>In-band regularization amount, 0..1 (default 0.5 — the verified setting). Scales the cancellation-band beta across ±1 decade: lower buys deeper rejection with a hotter, more position-sensitive filter; higher trades rejection for robustness and headroom. </description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name='bypass' get='1' set='1' type='long' size='1' >
			<digest>Pass the input straight through (the A/B reference required by the listening protocol)</digest>
			<description>Pass the input straight through (the A/B reference required by the listening protocol). Toggling ramps over one signal vector, so it does not click. Note the cancelled path carries the +12 dB-ceiling makeup attenuation and 512 samples of filter latency; loudness-match upstream for fair comparison. </description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name='distance' get='1' set='1' type='float64' size='1' >
			<digest>Listener-to-speaker distance in meters (>= 0.1)</digest>
			<description>Listener-to-speaker distance in meters (>= 0.1). Part of the stated geometry; the v1 symmetric far-field design is invariant to it (equal path delays and 1/r gains cancel), but state it truthfully — the robustness verification displaces the head against it. </description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name='span' get='1' set='1' type='float64' size='1' >
			<digest>Full angle between the loudspeakers in degrees (speakers at ±span/2), clamped to [5, 120]</digest>
			<description>Full angle between the loudspeakers in degrees (speakers at ±span/2), clamped to [5, 120]. Default 20 — the ±10° desktop geometry the verification gates run at. </description>
		</attribute>

	</attributelist>


	<!--RELATED-->

	<seealsolist>
		<seealso name='ambitap.binaural~' />
		<seealso name='ambitap.panbin~' />
		<seealso name='ambitap.decode~' />
	</seealsolist>


</c74object>
